travelmole.com 2016-06-08

# TravelMole - Privacy Policy

### TravelMole takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

Information Collection and Use  
Registration  
Order Forms  
Log Files  
Links  
Surveys & Contests  
Security  
Correcting/Updating Personal Information  
Notification of Changes  
Cookies  
Anti-Spam Policy  
Policy Regarding Advertising Our Website

All User information supplied by Users of TravelMole.com as defined under TravelMole.com Terms & Conditions is covered by the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) and U.K.'s amended Privacy and Electronic Communication Regulations (PECR) Act 2011.

### Information Collection and Use

We collect information from our users at several different points on the website - this is for customer service and billing purposes, we also collect data from our users so that we can customise the content and/or advertising site according to individual preferences. User details will be used only to provide service(s) specifically requested by the User.  User information will not be disclosed to a third party without Users’ permission, except when:  
We have your consent to share the information;  
We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of TravelMole to provide a product or service to you; (Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us.);  
We need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested;  
We respond to subpoenas, court orders, any legitimate request by authorities with which we must comply or legal process; or  
We find that your actions on our web sites violate our Terms and Conditions or any of our usage guidelines for specific products or services.  
TravelMole, as the sole owner of the personal information collected from this site, may transfer information about you if TravelMole acquires, or is acquired by or merged with, another company.

### Registration

In order to receive our newswires, email alerts or access our web site content, users have to complete a registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name, email address, industry sector, industry interests, etc.). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest and so we can provide a more personalised experience at TravelMole.com. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender).

### Order Forms

We request information from users on our order forms. Users have to provide contact information (such as name and delivery address) and financial information (such as credit card number and expiry date), only if the user is an advertiser or subscribing to a premium service. This information is used for billing purposes and to fulfill customer orders.

### Log Files

Whenever a User requests a page, username, IP address, browser and version and operating system are stored in a log file. This information is only used for statistical purposes to help improve this site and provide accurate statistics to advertisers in the form of aggregated data.

### Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that TravelMole is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of these third party sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose any information requested. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and delivery address), and demographic information (such as postcode, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving our services.

### Security

This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.  
When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, as will be the case for most of the time that a user is browsing the web.  
If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to service@travelmole.com

### Correcting/Updating Personal Information

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes, or if a user wished to change or discontinue their service, we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the personal profile page.

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

### Cookie Policy

We use cookies and similar technologies on our web sites to improve performance and make your experience better. 

Your use of our web sites indicates your consent to the cookies described in this policy. Please see HOW YOU CAN CONTROL COOKIES, below, for more information on how to withdraw your consent at any time. 

### WHAT ARE COOKIES?

A web cookie, a commonly used data collection technology, is simply a piece of text which can be placed on the browser of your personal computer or mobile device and subsequently read as you visit a web site. A cookie may be a session cookie, that is, a cookie that remains on your browser while you are logged on to a particular web site and then disappears when you close your browser, or it may be a persistent cookie, a cookie that remains on your browser over a period of time. Information from a cookie may be collected and used in aggregate form. Or data may be collected into an individual profile or record. That individual record may either be unique but anonymous, or the profile can be linked with information that identifies you as an individual.

You can learn more about cookies, generally, at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://privacypolicy.ubm.com/cookiepolicy/www.allaboutcookies.org)

### **HOW DO WE USE COOKIES?**

We may use cookies for a number of purposes:

**1\. Essential cookies**  
We may use a limited number of cookies essential to particular services you have requested or for security purposes. A few of our sites use a cookie for a shopping cart function when you purchase services or offerings. In particular, if you have registered for a site or use a customer portal we may use a cookie to authenticate the pc or mobile device that you are using.

**2\. Performance cookies**  
We allow third parties to set analytics, or performance, cookies to collect and report aggregate information. These cookies provide reporting to us on an aggregate basis and so, do not identify you at all. We use the aggregate reports to understand how our web sites are used and improve their usefulness to our audiences.

**3\. Functional cookies**  
A number of cookies also support how our web sites function, identifying your pc or end device on a unique but anonymous basis. These cookies may, for example, remember your language preferences or recognize an individual’s activity within a single session. 

If you register for a site, we use a cookie to associate your presence with a specific user name and password or account. We may use a persistent cookie to recognize you automatically each time you return, but only if you ask us to do so. We may also use cookies to prepopulate your login or forms you fill out on the site with information you have already provided. 

We may conduct analyses of user traffic to measure the use of our sites and to improve the content of our web sites and our services. These analyses will be performed through the use of IP addresses and cookies. 

We use web beacons and pixels in our emails to track delivery and open rates. Our email provider delivers cookies with our email to recognise a user’s response. The results are stored and reported on against the individual’s email address and the account profile within our database. 

### **THIRD PARTY COOKIES AND ADVERTISING ON OUR SITES**

We allow third party advertisers, such as Google, to show you advertising on our sites. Third party ad servers may use cookies to control certain routine advertising concerns such as making sure that you do not see the same ad too many times or that the ads are shown in the format best suited for your browser. Advertising may also be targeted: You may be shown ads based on certain demographic information which we provide, for example, the size of the company you work for or your professional responsibilities. Advertisers may also use third party ad servers to target you based on an anonymous but unique profile on your online behavior across a number of unaffiliated websites, a method known as online behavioral advertising. Advertisers may even place their own cookies on our sites. You can find more information about each ad server’s practices by reviewing its privacy policies, for our sites, [DoubleClick](http://support.google.com/dfp_premium/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=2551880) and [Google AdSense](http://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=1348695). 

We may use certain demographic information to enable third party ad servers (see below) to show you ads based on information about you in your business capacity, for example, your title within a company or the size of that company. 

Finally, we ask both ad servers, DoubleClick and Google AdSense, to use their cookies on our sites to identify you as you leave and then to show you one of our own ads later, as you visit another site. This relatively simple process is known as re-targeting. 

### **HOW YOU CAN CONTROL COOKIES**

The cookies we use or allow are an accepted part of ecommerce and important to your use of our web sites. Performance cookies allow us to understand our audiences as a whole and improve how our sites meet your needs and expectations. Many of the functional cookies are basic to how our sites and services work. The cookies we use for registration allow us to conduct our business online. Our sites and services, or parts of them, may not work properly without these cookies.

**Browser controls**  
Most modern browsers offer you ways to control or block cookies. These browser controls will usually be found in the “options’ or “preferences” menu. For more help, you may take a look at the “Help” settings or review these website for more details -<http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1>

### **ANTI-SPAM POLICY**

Spam, or unsolicited emails (usually sent in bulk), are a common problem in the digital age. TravelMole.com has a zero-tolorance policy regarding spam emails.

Automated software systems running on the TravelMole servers automatically scan all incoming email and filter known and likely spam emails. No software is perfect however so if you believe your legitimate email was caught in our spam software, please try again by either using a different email address or by sending a plain-text email with no attachements.

Continued spamming to TravelMole addresses will be reported and IP's of gross spammers will be blocked

TravelMole sends millions of emails out each year to our subscribers. If you receive any email that you do not want (a frequent cause of this is a TravelMole subscriber leaving a business and that subscriber's emails auto-forward to another employee), simply hit the unsubscribe option found in every one of our emails or forward the email to [support@travelmole.com](mailto:support@travelmole.com) with the subject line changed to "Unsubscribe". Alternativly, you can email [support@travelmole.com](mailto:support@travelmole.com) with the email address in question and title the email "Unsubscribe this address".

All unsubscribe or abuse requests are investigated by TravelMole staff and are promptly addressed.

If you have any questions about our anti-spam policy or wish to report anything to the TravelMole support staff, please email us at [support@travelmole.com](mailto:support@travelmole.com).

### **POLICY REGARDING ADVERTISING OUR WEBSITE**

Any email sent regarding, promoting or otherwise describing TravelMole.com or any affiliated sites (such as TravelMole.tv, TravelMole.net, TravelMole.info, or TravelMole.mobi) must be sent only to individuals or subscribers who have agreed to receive such messages. Any advertising of our website, brand or logo through unsolicited email messages is strictly prohibited. 

Failure to comply with this policy is grounds for termination of any partnership, business agreement, or trade agreement. Any individual subscriber found to have ignored or abused this policy will have their account terminated.

If you have received any communication you believe may be an unsolicited email promoting or mentioning our brand, website or logo and would like to report the abuse, please email us at [support@travelmole.com](mailto:support@travelmole.com). Any complaint regarding possible abuse will be promptly and thoroughly investigated.

### **THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If our use of cookies changes, we will post the changes to this policy. Please check frequently as online data collection practices and our use of them continue to evolve. To contact us about this policy, you may email [support@travelmole.com](mailto:support@travelmole.com).  When emailing please indicate which of our sites your question relates to.
